Rene A. Cocom, Jr.

Chicago, IL 60645 | 312-890-6166 | racocom@gmail.com | Github | LinkedIn | Website

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software Engineer that utilized Boot Camp experience and Freelance Graphic design client management to connect and be a valuable member of multiple client projects at IBM. Graduated apprenticeship program to become an Associate Application Developer and learn to work with client and project workflows improving professional approach and task delivery. Built vital customer service and communication skills through client engagement and training.

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Ruby | Ruby on Rails | Javascript | React | Angular | Java | Junit | SQL | PostgreSQL | HTML | CSS

DESIGN SKILLS

Adobe Illustrator | Adobe Indesign | Adobe XD | Adobe Photoshop | Adobe Premiere Pro | Adobe LightRoom

EXPERIENCE

IBM Application Development

Baton Rouge, LA May 2021 - Present

- Angular programming language was used in the majority of my projects to used to build clients' SAP storefronts to develop features
- UX/UI creating interactive media, using Angular framework and connecting to API
- Designed UX/UI features for user experience to interact with webpages features for the site to handle users' input in payment checkout, forms, homepage, and navigation.
- Moderated high to low-priority tasks through Agile framework user stories which are tasks divided up into the more manageable task
- SAP Cloud Development was my primary role where I was a part of client data migration
- Built SAP Backoffice an interface to cover products, client logins, and client's customer info interface
- Used SmartEdit to help clients edit website content, and images
- Implemented SAP Backoffice configurations to boot products and promotions
- Used Junit when working as a tester
- Migrated client data using Hybris standers from Stibo to Commerce Cloud
- Used development best practice skills to ensure Agile workflow

Freelance Graphic Designer

Chicago, IL

Independent Freelancer

June 2018 - April 2020

- Built a professional-level active portfolio using the Adobe Suite, including Photoshop and XD for business and
- XD used to implement UI and UX design for Web Applications for mobile and desktop dimensions
- Photoshop used to edit and create clients' created expressions
- Typography to create custom fonts and styling
 - Typographical fonts were used to explore and create a brand identity for clients
- Photoshop and Adobe LightRoom used to enhance clients' photography and other creative works
- Using Adobe Illustrator for art covers for digital and printable materials

EDUCATION

Flatiron Software Engineering Certification

New York, NY June 2019 - October 2020

- Created open-source projects using modern languages, including Javascript, Ruby, and React, while working alongside experienced industry professionals. Utilized modern ES6 standards, including useState and React Router Dom for page and site navigation.
- Developed full slack applications with API and Client-Side interface.
- Built an O-Auth authorization as a part of a project to protect users' data database.
- Deployed learned project using Heroku and Github
- Created a React final project that implemented a Rails API, and was created to have users interact with a personalized search profile.

IBM Garage Essentials

July 22nd, 2022

CERTIFICATION

Flatiron School	Chicago, IL
Certificate: Software Engineering	October 2020
IBM Baton Rouge, LA	
Certificates:	
IBM Agile Explorer	June 30th, 2021
Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner	June 13th, 2021
Application Developer Apprentice	March 8th, 2022
IBM Apprenticeship Program - Professional Skills	March 7th, 2022
Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals	June 29th, 2021
Agile Explorer Badge	June 30th, 2021
Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner	June 13th, 2021
 Open Source Participation Guidelines Apprentice Launchpad Skills 	June 14th, 2021
 SAP Commerce Cloud Business User Training Formerly Hy200 	June 22nd, 2021
 GitHub Ultimate: Master Git and GitHub – Beginner to Expert 	June 17th, 2021
IBM Garage Foundation	July 22nd, 2022

REFERENCES

Isaac Duraisingh

Complex Program Manager-Digital Customer Experience & BRIM(Industrial IX) Consulting isaacduraisingh@us.ibm.com

Nick DeriseBaton Rouge, LASoftware Application Developer at IBMnick.derise@ibm.com

Laura DurioBaton Rouge, LATechnical Business Analyst, Package Consultant, and Scrum Master at IBMlaura.durio@ibm.com

Aparna Penumatcha

Baton Rouge, LA
Certified SAP Commerce Cloud Package Solution Consultant at IBM aparna.penumatcha@ibm.com

Aysan IsayoWashington, DCLecturer, Software Engineering at Flatiron Schoolaysanisayo@outlook.com

Ben LappenLos Angeles, CASoftware Coach at Flatiron Schoolben.lappen@flatironschool.com

Candice PetersChicago, ILBackend Associate at BORN Groupcandicepcodes@gmail.com